

## **NWOKOMA EMMANUEL**

Software Developer

+2348158576171 nwokomaemmanuel@gmail.com

https://linkedin.com/in/emmanuelnwokoma https://www.github.com/enwokoma

## Summary

Experienced in designing and developing software for business solutions.

A software developer with experience in multiple settings, can design and develop programs using the latest and most appropriate technology.

Also a web developer specializing in both frontend and backend development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including: JAVA, Kotlin, PHP, JavaScript, Bash and VB.NET. Strong background in project management and customer relations. Successful at marketing techniques. Knowledgeable about digital media platforms and deadline-oriented editing. Through these qualities, I have confidence in my ability to facilitate positive change and collaborative effort.

### Skills

- LANGUAGES: Kotlin, JAVA, PHP, Golang, Bash, VB.NET
- APPLICATIONS: Android Studio, PHPStorm, PyCharm, WebStorm, MS Visual Studio, Eclipse.
- APPLICATION SERVERS: JBoss, Apache Tomcat
- OPERATING SYSTEMS: Windows, Unix, Linux
- DATABASE SYSTEMS: SQL Server, MySQL, Ingres, PostgreSQL
- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver

- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused
- Strong organizational and prioritization skills along with keen attention to detail.
- Good interpersonal and organizational skills, with an ability to work both independently and collaboratively.

## Experience

Lead Developer - 02/2016 to 07/2019 SHOPPING SAMRAT, India (remote)

Lead developer for the development of ecommerce store, shoppingsamrat.com.

#### Responsible for:

- Developing of the website using OOP PHP.
- Supporting further releases developed in ASP.
- Adapting and adjusting graphic packages from other regions.
- Working closely with the writer producers and editors.
- Strong creative and conceptual vision and excellence in Typography.

# Senior Software Developer and Chief Technical Officer - 08/2016 – present OJALAWA, Lagos (Nigeria) – remote, onsite

A senior executive (CTO) with sole responsibility for managing the technological requirements of ecommerce startup (Ojalawa), currently developing its online store, ojalawa.com.

Ojalawa is a startup, an online food market dedicated to the supply of groceries around Lagos State.

#### Responsible for:

- Complete development of the website using Magento.
- Development of a mobile application for Android.
- Leading development team for framework designing.
- Developing project concepts and maintaining optimal workflow.
- Carrying out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

#### Highlight:

• In spite of very tight schedules and limited resources, the e-store was fully developed from scratch and was online for an extensive beta testing.

## Co-Founder and Chief Executive Officer - 12/2015 – present GIGABYTE DEVELOPERS, Abia State (Nigeria)

A senior executive (CEO) with sole responsibility for overseeing all client projects handled and managed by Gigabyte Developers as a notable fast-growing software development company in the southeast established to create first class, high quality, low cost, easy to use products that incorporate top class technologies for every single individual.

#### Responsible for:

- Managing the development team.
- Providing statistical and performance feedback illustrated in charts.
- Coaching and administering performance reviews for proper skill improvement.

#### Highlights:

- Successfully completed 27 projects.
- Completed development of 9 mobile applications within 18 months.
- Over 65 happy clients in a period of 4 years.
- Over 10,000 people make use of our software solutions directly or indirectly.

# Bioresources and Research Intern - 03/2016 to 10/2016 NATIONAL ROOT CROPS RESEARCH INSTITUTE, Umudike, Abia State (Nigeria)

Industrial training and research internship on bioresources.

#### Responsible for:

- Worked on several research projects.
- Providing statistical and performance data illustrated in charts.
- Cooperated with colleagues to develop a thesis on the utility of bioresources in modern-day biotechnology.

# Chief Information Officer - 10/2019 – present OCTOFI, Anambra State (Nigeria)

Octofi provides fast and reliable internet service to homes, offices and individuals via WiFi.

## **Highlighted Projects**

- SONSHUB MOBILE

It is a mobile application for streaming and downloading gospel media contents. **Technologies Used**: Android Studio, Kotlin, Java, RxJava, RxAndroid

FIREFILES

FireFiles is an all-in-one (AIO) file management tool for mobile.

Technologies Used: Android Studio, Java, RxJava, Dagger

COMETOTP (OTP Authenticator for Android)

CometOTP implements Time-based One-time Passwords (TOTP) like specified in RFC 6238 and HMAC-based One-time Passwords (HOTP) algorithms to generate 2-Step Verification codes on your phone.

Technologies Used: Android Studio, Kotlin, Java, OpenPGP, HOTP, TOTP

## Other Projects

Some other projects I worked on can be found here:

https://plav.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=4617962611760843834

### Education

NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY, NIGERIA

Bachelor's Degree in Botany (July, 2018)

### Certification

**DIGITAL MARKETING, GOOGLE** 

Certificate issued by Google (June, 2019)

Cert ID: EL4W2LAV6

**ANALYTICS**, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: **49895602** 

ADS SEARCH, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: **49891218** 

#### **DISPLAY & VIDEO 360, GOOGLE**

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: <u>49909629</u>

#### SEARCH ADS 360, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: **49908705** 

#### **CAMPAIGN MANAGER**, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: <u>49897032</u>

#### **CREATIVE CERTIFICATION, GOOGLE**

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: <u>49897053</u>

### Personal Details

**DATE OF BIRTH**: 27<sup>th</sup> May, 1998

LANGUAGES: English, Igbo, Spanish

ADDRESS: 40, Nnokwa Street, World Bank Housing Estate, Umuahia, Abia State